Listen, I did $50,000 in one trade. That
That's the power of the model. You just
have to wait. It was a one to 51. I have
the highest payout in the history of the
firm and it was a $51,000 and I risked
$1,000 off
cuz each of these candlesticks is
telling a different story. Like if this
candle closed here, right? Say this
wasn't a dogee. The body of this candle
was in here. This would be an
invalidation. Like I wouldn't take the
setup. I want to see a dogee candle.
Why? Because the
>> Today we have a very special guest.
someone who has jumped onto the trading
scene and taken it by storm, closing in
on almost 400,000 in payouts in just
three months while also having close to
400,000 currently within his Apex
accounts, too. This is a very high
riskto-reward strategy breakdown that
we're going to be doing today. And
without further ado, it is the one and
only TG Capital, aka Tyler.
But if you just stay patient and you
wait for this setup, I promise you it
could change your entire life.
Literally, it did to me. And listen,
based on my data, I can get maybe 8 to
10 entries a year. I typically like to
use like a 10 pip stop loss.
>> The risk-to-reward minimum that I'm
taking on that trades is a 1 to 20.
Normally, the only thing I will say with
gold, I don't use a hard stop loss. I
will wait for a close below this candle
because this is the indicator I told you
guys about where it's showing the
bullish candles. I'll actually bring the
indicator up. It's called I'm telling
you right now, if you're patient enough
to and you can nail this strategy down,
it'll set you financially free 100%.
>> Welcome back everyone to Chart Fanatics,
the go-to channel for all the very best
trading strategies in the world with the
very best traders in the world. And
today we have a very special guest.
Someone who has jumped onto the trading
scene and taken it by storm, closing in
on almost 400,000 in payouts in just 3
months while also having close to
400,000 currently within his Apex
accounts, too. He's crushed the CFD
space. He's currently taking over the
future space. This is a very high
riskto-reward strategy breakdown that
we're going to be doing today. And
without further ado, it is the one and
only TG Capital aka Tyler. Great to be
here with you, man.
>> I'm super excited to be here. It's a
dream come true for me, to be honest.
>> It's my pleasure.
>> I I even reached out to you in the DM. I
was like, I was going to be on one of
these with you one day, and it was a
goal for me, and I'm just glad to be
here with you today. Talk it out.
>> My pleasure. Where should we begin,
then?
>> Let's We're going to go with I have a
few setups that I that I utilize, but
let's for the sake of today, let's just
go over the one that I utilize to make
the most amount of money.
>> Yeah. So, the first thing that I'm going
to write here is that before anything,
we're we're strictly going to be trading
in the London kill zone. So, I'll write
out here, we're only going to be trading
London
from the hours of 3:00 a.m. And this is
all NY time, okay? To And I'll usually
stop looking for entries at around 6:30
a.m. So, right when like New York
crosses over, that's when I'll stop
looking for my entries.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So once we have the kill zone
established, we're only going to be
trading on one time frame. Why? To keep
it simple. So we're only going to be
trading
the 30 minute time frame.
>> Interesting.
>> And we're going to use for our
takeprofit, we're going to use the daily
chart. So the daily is our TP
because why? We want to know the overall
narrative of the market and we want to
uh go with the higher time frame
structure. So to me the 30 minute is
still low time frame. like to each his
own. Anything below the hour for me is
is still low time frame. So this is what
are going to be our main focus here. So
before any TA or any price action, we
need these these uh this to be
established. So once I know that now I'm
going to come into the market. I have a
few indicators that I utilize cuz I I'm
more of trading with the trend. And I'm
going to also state this. The most
amount of money that I made, I am a long
biased trader. So, I'm mostly taking
longs or looking for longs. I'm not good
at shorting. I just based on my back
testing and my data, I'm just not a good
good at shorting. I don't know. Just I
have years of data from it and most of
my money came from longs and especially
on naturally bullish assets like gold
and and the NASDAQ. So, I I'm taking
advantage of a naturally occurring
bullish asset in the market and then
just simply waiting. That's the that's
the problem that a lot of people have is
that they don't have the patience. They
need to feel like they need to be in the
markets all the time. And for me, that's
where I really struggled at first is
that I was looking for a trade every
single day on the lower time frames. And
then when I scaled back and I really
just focused more on the higher time
frames, then I really saw a lot of
success and actually snowballed and
happened from really really fast.
>> So less is truly more. I may it may
sound like a cliche statement, but it
really did work for me.
>> Hey guys, just a very very quick one. If
you're enjoying this playbook and you
want to get it sent directly to you,
make sure to go on chart fanatics.com,
put your email in, and every episode we
drop, we will send you a direct PDF
breaking down this exact playbook. Or
alternatively, also the playbooks will
be put all together with the rules over
on Trade Zella. That is an incredible
collaboration. So, if you want to
actually add the playbook to your
Tradezella, make sure you go check that
out as well. But let's get back into
this episode. So, going on here now, I'm
going to I'm going to go with a
different market here. So, I have a few
EMAs that I use. So, I'm going to try
and draw this out for you guys so you
can really visualize it. And then when I
pull up the charts, you'll see.
>> Yeah.
>> So, okay. So, it's 3 3:00 a.m. and I'm
coming to the charts. Right.
>> Here's this is a 5 EMA. This is a I
think it's a nine I use. And then this
is a a 13.
and then a 21. Okay. So, and for for the
sake of the conversation, we're only
going to be focusing on on a long
position. I do take shorts, but let's go
with my A+ long long setup. So, now when
I come into the market,
um, you see how all these EMAs here, the
the five, the 9, the 13, and the 21,
they're all stacking. So, it's showing
strong bullish structure already. If
they were intertwining like this, if the
EMAs were crossing like here, I wouldn't
be interested in any price action that
has to do with that because it's a low
probability condition.
>> Definitely.
>> So now, when I come to the market, I'm
looking for 3:00 a.m. hits here. What do
I see? I see a fair value gap here,
printing on the 3 a.m. candle, right?
>> Mhm.
>> Let's just say it was a small wick here.
Okay. And then you have another candle
here and then another candle here, like
this, right? So, after I see that,
that's my first sign. So, this is I'm
already watching the market. Once I see,
it doesn't have to be at 3:00 a.m., but
based on my data, when the candle is at
3:00 a.m. or 2:30 or 3:30, it's normally
really, really highly probable that the
trade is going to go in my direction.
So, now what do I want to see next? I
came up with something. It's going to
sound weird, but I call it a trident
pattern. So, yeah, I I just came up with
a name with it so I could help myself
uh, you know, uh, understand it and look
for it in the market. So after I see my
fair value gap printing, I'm then going
to look for it's going to be a dogee
candle, right? And it's going to this is
the fair value gap here. Okay.
>> Now, this is what ICT calls it's the
consequent encroachment or the 50%.
Yeah.
>> If I get a dogee candle here, especially
a wick that wicks through it and I have
my EMAs aligned and I'm also seeing this
strong fair value gap and then the next
candle after this dogee candle closes
below this high, right? If it closes
above the high, I'll I'll I'll
invalidate the trade just based on my
data. It does it's not as highly
probable as as this. So when this closes
here,
>> I'm like all in. So I see this I'm
entering here. My stop loss would be
below this candle low here, right? And
then I would jump to the daily time
frame and then I would look for my TP.
And my TPS could be huge. They could be
like
>> the biggest uh trade I've ever had was
on Think Capital. It was a 1 to 51 on a
U trade. Yeah, I I had the highest
payout in the history of the firmc and
it was a $51,000 and I risked $1,000 on
my 200k account. Yeah, it was insane,
bro. And I actually just closed another
payout was like 12,000. So, I'm working
my way to 100K with them. So, but yeah,
that when you see it on the chart, it's
kind of hard for me to write. I'm trying
my best for you guys, but when you see
it on the chart, it's going to look a
lot cleaner. I actually have multiple
setups like this. But if you just stay
patient and you wait for this setup, I
promise you, it could change your entire
life. Literally, it it it did to me. And
listen, based on my data, I can get
maybe 8 to 10 entries a year per pair.
So, I'm trading the USD pairs. So, UKAD,
NZDUSD, Euro USD, GBPUSD, and USD uh
JPY. I don't trade AUDUSD because in my
back testing it didn't work well.
>> Okay.
>> But the biggest wins that I have are on
gold
>> really.
>> That's the most money I've ever made is
is trading gold. Especially now with the
market conditions as you're seeing on
gold, it's like holy cow. So if you just
wait simply for this setup and you wait
for the right time, this setup means
nothing without the time. I want to
stress that heavily
>> because without time, you're literally
the price action means absolutely
nothing. And the person who taught me
that the most is ICT because I was
looking for trades at all hours of the
day. You know what I mean? Like at low
probability times like 2:00 in the
afternoon. It's like a fair value got
printed then it's not as highly probable
as a fair value got printed in in the
opening of a London session kill zone.
You know what I mean? So that when you
>> now that you're coming to the market at
at such a small time like for me this is
only about 3 hours and you're focusing
on a smaller window you can now maximize
and look and be like okay these are the
candlesticks that I want to see cuz each
of these candlesticks is telling a
different story. Each of them has their
own narrative. Like if this candle
closed here, right? Say this wasn't a
dogee and this the body of this candle
was in here and it did and it this would
be an invalidation. Like I wouldn't take
the setup. I want to see a dogee candle.
Why? Because the sellers tried to come
down here, right? Yeah.
>> But there was such strong bullish price
action that they came all the way back
here. So it's already telling you now
it's telling you the narrative of the
market. The market wants to go higher.
>> So don't try and predict the market.
just react to it.
>> Yes.
>> So, let the market do what it's got to
do and then you can get involved in the
market.
>> And in terms of the EMA, so you're just
using them for the correlation of like
the momentum.
>> Exactly. It's basically like I use it I
kind of utilize it as like a wave. So, I
want to see them all stacking cuz it's
showing, okay, price is already feeling
very bullish for me and now I get the
candle confirmation on top of that with
>> being on the 30-minut time frame, which
is an a higher time frame and I'm
aligning it with the daily. It's like
this is a home run. Like I could I'm not
kidding. On these setups my win rate is
really high like 90%.
>> Wow.
>> And you just got to wait. Like that's
the problem with most people. They'll
take an invalidated setup. Like I used
to take all of these setups and then I
refined the strategy more and more and
more to the point where it became
bulletproof. Like it's that good.
>> So that's why when people tell me it's
like you never lose, you never lose.
Well, I did lose. I also took an a year
break from prop firms when I was failing
and I focused solely on back testing
this edge to the point where I knew that
I was going to be successful. Like I
when I finally back tested this to the
point where I knew it was that good. I
put $20,000 on all my credit cards right
on challenges. I maxed out every single
credit card I had. My parents told me I
was a psycho. I said I had so much
self-belief to the point where I was
delusional. I passed every single
challenge and my first big payout was
with instant funding. I made $20,000.
After I made that $20,000, I quit my
job. I was in the elevator union in New
York and I moved to Miami. I was that I
was sick in the head. And then as soon
as I moved to Miami, right, I made my
first I had my first six figure month. I
And it snowballed to the point where I
had two consecutive six figuring months.
Then like now I made like over like
close to $400,000 in payouts. It's like
it's happening for me really really
really fast. And especially like with
social media and everything too, it's
like I had the growth I had in such a
small amount of time is that anybody can
achieve that. You just got to put the
work in and then trust your system. Like
I'm focus solely focusing on the
mathematics of my system. My edge is
really really good in the market.
>> So whenever I see a setup and my edge is
there, I'm taking it.
>> No, definitely. And you know what's that
in terms of the transitions? This is on
the USD pairs, right? So we go grab
this.
>> Yeah.
>> Do so this is
>> USD pairs and then gold. Yes.
>> Yeah. And uh in terms of this, so like
you said, if this invalidates
invalidates a trade if you get a close
below rather than the dogee candle,
right? Yes. And then your stop loss is
below this level here.
>> Yes.
>> And then your TP you said on the daily,
what would you be looking for in terms
of TP?
>> Like my minimum TP. Okay. Even if you
solely wanted to focus on the on the
30-inut time frame.
>> Yeah.
>> So most of my stop losses are between
like for USD pairs for like GU, EU, USD
CAD, and NZDUSD. I typically like to use
like a 10 pip stop loss.
>> Okay.
>> And like the risk-to-reward minimum that
I'm taking on their trades is a 1 to 20.
>> Really?
>> Yeah. I know it sounds crazy, but I made
it to the point where I'm having a high
RR and a high win rate. I know a lot of
people say that it's not possible, but
it is because I've done it.
>> Well, you're doing it. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Normally, the only thing I will
say with gold, I don't use a hard stop
loss. I will wait for a close below this
candle because what I noticed with gold
and strictly on my back testing is that
it has a lot of liquidity wicks. Yeah.
>> And it's extremely volatile pair. So
sometimes,
>> okay, I get this, say I get this setup,
right? The next candle could drive like
this.
>> It could be like here, and then I could
get a wick all the way down here, and
then it could close back up.
>> Yeah.
>> And this is just a liquidity wick for it
to build more for it to build uh get
more buyers into the market. Stop out
everyone here, and then go a lot higher.
I've had it happen countless times and
I've had I have over a years of data
with it and I just noticed that with
>> uh gold I strictly um don't use a hard
stop loss. I'll wait for a candle close.
>> So
>> So if it closes if the candle
>> if the candle closes below I'm out.
>> Okay, got you. Let's take a break for a
minute there guys cuz I want to tell you
about our preferred prop firm here at
Chart Fanatics and it is Apex Trader
Funding. We are no stranger to Apex.
We've had Jadecap and Trader Kane on
Words of Wisdom and here on Chart
Fanatics. Now, they are well known for
having record payouts on Apex of over $2
million a piece. Now, even if you don't
achieve a seven figure payout, the
reality of achieving a multi6igure
payouts with Apex is absolutely
achievable and an incredible opportunity
at that. And you can see that on screen
right now with all the incredible
payouts being paid out to traders around
the world, traders just like you. Now,
Apex is the biggest futures firm in the
entire industry and have paid out over
$500 million to traders across the
world. No matter the type of trader, you
can be one of them, too. Now, one of our
favorite things about Apex is that you
can get up to $6 million in funding
using the 20 accounts that you're
allowed to have and the 300K account at
that that totals $6 million. And another
thing that we love about Apex is that
there's no daily draw down. It's a
one-step evaluation and the fact that is
uncapped payouts and 90% of the profits
made are yours to keep. Now, don't
forget, regardless of the type of trader
that you are, you do not have to worry
about trading news as long as you are
following your day-to-day trading
strategy. The possibilities are
limitless at Apex Trader Funding. Now
you can get up to 90% off. 90% off the
biggest discount in the entire industry
at Apex using the code CF and the link
in the description below. Thanks to them
and thanks to Chart Fanatics. Make sure
you get your futures funding with Apex.
Now, let's get back to the episode.
>> But gold is usually my best pair,
especially with longs. It's a naturally
bullish asset. Same with uh ENQ. So,
>> no, definitely. No, definitely. Have you
run into any problems in terms of having
no stop on gold when it comes to the
firms?
>> No. Uh, not really. I haven't like I
won't trade a firm unless they have they
have those rules.
>> Yeah. I don't trade with firms that have
a stop-loss rule. I think it's like to
be honest. And then you got to place it
within a certain amount of time. I just
don't like there are a lot of f like
literally I'm burn I'm banned from like
over 25 firms
>> really.
>> Yeah. I can't trade with any of them
really anymore. So, and the thing is is
that once I got one big payout with one
>> and then I started showing it on social
media, I feel like it all caught wind.
>> Yeah. They won't let me buy account.
Like some firms don't even let me buy
accounts.
>> They don't say anything. They just block
it. Right.
>> Well, a lot of the firms come up with
these arbitrary fake rules and they
breach my accounts or they just tell me
that I can't trade with them anymore.
And if you know a lot of these firms
that are in the space are white label
firms.
>> And once you get banned from one white
label firm, your name your name goes on
into a database and then either they
won't let you buy accounts or they won't
offer you funding. So you'll pass and
then they'll just deny you.
>> Definitely. So,
>> but this the beautiful thing is though
this is an actual edge. So, it's not a
case where you know some people where
that happens to them or most people when
that happens to them it's because they
the edge they have is a prop firm edge
if that makes sense.
>> It's like risk high and and I play the
model of like you know we'll spend 20k
on challenges but make 200k because
>> I'm going to be honest my allin with
challenges even from when I burn them
when I was first going through it is
probably $15,000. So, I my
ROI on my investment is pretty big. So,
you know what I mean? But I will say
this, luckily, like with all the the
things that have been going on and me
sharing my payouts, I'm having an
amazing experience with Alpha Prime
right now. Like, I'm loving it. The uh
the person who is in charge of it,
James, like we talk every single day. He
gives me a lot of good fundamental
analysis. We were just talking before
and it I'm loving it. like it's a dream
come true for me because now I'm trading
real funds and he wants to scale me to
like a seven figure account. So to go
from prop firms to now have the
opportunity to be in a live environment
and he plans on like I think I'm one of
six traders so far and he wants to get
this re he wants to make it huge
>> and I'm just loving the experience so
far and he wants to bring everyone
together to like you know say like you
have a trader he has a few traders from
Singapore some from uh Boston a few from
California and he wants to bring us in a
group where we could share our TA and
see if it aligns and see if you could
learn something from other people. It's
just a really really cool thing and I'm
just so glad to be a part of it because
I always wanted to have you know be
involved in something now I have the
opportunity to.
>> In terms of uh the model then so daily
time frame wise um you know in terms of
targets what is it that you would
identify on the daily time frame to
target.
>> So on the daily I'm looking for the same
exact structure here with the EMAs
>> just on a just on a daily chart. So you
know what I mean? So, if if I see this.
Okay. So, say we get the 30 minute setup
and then we have let's let's do the EMAs
again, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Hold on. We'll do the EMAs here. Now,
this is the daily chart, mind you. Okay.
>> Yeah. Let me get rid of this one here.
This is a
>> Now, so you're getting Let me get the
black one.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you. And then, so you have the
confirmed setup on the 30 minute and
then your daily.
Now, this is all occurring inside of
this daily candle. Remember that.
>> So, say this daily candle is here. And I
have another indicator I'm going to show
you guys is actually a really good one.
>> It shows you how the candle closes. So,
if it's a if it's strong, if it's a
strong bullish candle, it's going to
close a a bright green. If it's a a
bullish candle, but it's not extremely
strong, it'll close blue. If it's a
bearish candle and it's strong, it'll
close red. And if it's a a bearish
candle, it's not extreme like not a lot
of high volume, it's going to close
black. Actually, a friend that I used to
work with, he showed me this indicator.
Works really really well. And I just
utilize it to help me just add an extra
confluence. Like I don't rely on
indicators, but if I could add a
confluence to the trade, I add it. So,
so say I'm on the daily chart and when I
pull up my charts, you'll see it.
>> This candle is is here on the daily,
right? Yeah.
>> And it's closing green.
>> It has a
>> This is how it's printing right now. and
then I get this setup inside of it, I
know that this is going to move huge.
>> Okay?
>> And so, usually I'll just ride the trend
until like the EMAs cross over
>> or if I get like a a a large bearish
candle, then I'll cut it cuz then I know
I know like say the candle closes red or
I get like a
>> So, it's kind of like your management
technique as well.
>> It's the same thing.
>> Yeah. So, I'm just I'm utilizing the
lower time frame to get in on the daily.
>> So, I'm analyzing what's going on inside
of this candle. So this candle's already
strong for me, but then if I see this
inside the candle, then I know it that's
my confirmation to go long. Yeah.
>> You understand?
>> Yeah. No, 100%. And then in terms of
your targeting wise, are you targeting
like u external liquidity?
>> Correct. Or I'll just ride the trend for
as long as I can. So if the if the trend
ends after it takes out some some sort
of liquidity, I'll just cut it.
>> And most of the times when I'm trading
props, I it gets to a point where I'm
like, "Okay, this payout's going to be
huge and I'll have to cut it." Like I
that's why I cut the like on my Thin
Capital when I was up $50,000. The trade
was still going to go,
>> but I I didn't think that they were
going to pay me six figures in one shot,
so I cut it.
>> No, I'm being for real. It's why that
trade ran like it I knew it was going to
go lower, but I was like, "All right,
let me be safe here." It was my first
payout with them and I I took it. So,
normally I'll ride this for as long as I
can and then I'll just focus on if I get
like a IFVG like it invalidates a fair
value gap. What a what a strong bearish
candle. I'll be like, "All right, now
there's a chance that this is going to
reverse against me."
>> Yeah.
>> So, a little bit. It's not entirely um
mechanical. A little bit is um
discretionary.
>> Yeah.
>> Cuz like everyone's going to have their
own intuition in the markets. This is
just from something you can't teach
someone is having the time on the
charts. It's just I have that intuition
too of when I know when to cut the
trade. So, I'm not going to say it's a
100% mechanical all the time. This part
is for me. But as far as taking out like
liquidity and knowing when to get out,
that is a little bit discretionary. I
will admit that.
>> 100%. Yeah.
>> And so, I think that that's okay. Like
having an 8020 model, like that's how
most traders are going to succeed. I
feel like 100% mechanical models aren't
going to work all of the time.
>> No, definitely. And I think that 100%
mechanical, if that's the case, then you
might as well just make it into an algo.
Exactly.
>> Yeah. Don't have to worry about
>> Yeah. have to have listen the human
being is going to have a little bit more
of an edge over over 100% mechanical
model I feel cuz I've tried the
mechanical models and they don't work
all the time.
>> Yeah. No, definitely especially when
market conditions change.
>> Correct.
>> Right. Because then that's when the
discretion really comes in because you
know as we've seen between last year to
this year the markets are completely
different. The volatile uh the
volatility sorry is so much higher. And
with that then you need to make tweaks.
You need to make changes. Use discretion
based on obviously those changes to be
able to do so. Especially like you said,
you know, when it comes to take profits,
even when it comes to say a stop loss or
cutting a loss, that's discretion,
right? You know, when everyone always
says, you know, you have to cut your
your losses, you know, as early as
possible. That's discretion. Otherwise,
you just got to leave it to stop loss,
right?
>> Well, who who are they to say to cut
your losses early? Everyone's process
and system is entirely different. Like
the way I trade and the way I see the
markets, this is what I tell everyone on
Twitter who are asking me.
>> You guys, even if you have this system,
right, you still may never trade it the
same way as me. You won't. It's just the
way it is. everyone. This is an
individualized thing. You have to find
what works for you. Like I I'm patient
and I tried the lower time frames. It
doesn't work for me. It's too much on my
psychology.
>> But some people are great at scalping.
They're great at the lower time frames.
It's just not something that ever worked
for me. So, I do want to stress that is
that you can take my what I teach you
here, but maybe implement it in a way
where it works for you. You know what
I'm saying? That's how I became
successful. I took bits and pieces from
a lot of different people and then I
made it my own. So, I took the models.
what what ICT, you know, taught me in
his mentorships and I made it 100%
something that's suitable for me. I'm
not good at trading order blocks. I'm
good at recognizing fair value gaps and
in inverted fair value gaps. So, I
utilize that. You know what I mean? You
just take what works for you. Like a
friend of mine, he trades um breakers. I
don't even know what a breaker is to be
honest. I It's just everyone's
different,
>> you know? So, you just got to find what
works for you.
>> Big part of what you said though is that
you spent that time to collect data. you
know, you understand the maths of your
model. And I think that's the biggest
difference because even again, as you
said, someone could be watching this
right now, understanding it all. We're
going to go on the charts and break it
down there as well. But even then, they
still, regardless of whether they've
seen it, they need to go and get the
data themselves, collect that data
themselves because for them, it might be
a case where, you know, through that
data, even though it's the same setup,
they might notice that they're better at
shorts.
>> Exactly.
>> You know, they're completely the same
model, just the opposite direction, and
it might end up being the same thing.
But London wise, is that the only
session you focus on or you looking at
New York as well? Only?
>> No, I'm looking I'm only looking at
London. Why? Because the data showed me
that the highest probability setups are
in London. So, I just I don't fix what's
not broken. That's it. I just wait
patiently. I come to the market for
this,
>> you know, few hours every single day.
And, you know, I got to wake up early.
It's not the best. But the reason why I
started trading London is because when I
was in the elevator union, I started at
six o'clock in the morning. So, I was
trading before and I was like, "All
right, how can I make London work?" And
I liked the volume in London. I thought
it was clean. The price action was clean
and then I can get the continuation in
New York. So, it's just what I preferred
and and what it's worked. So, I don't
I'm not going to change my model. I just
stick to it. It's generated me this much
in profit so far, so I'm good with it,
you know.
>> Definitely. No, I can imagine.
Definitely. Cool. Um, let's should we go
into the the sort of pros and cons?
Let's take a break for a minute there,
guys, because I want to tell you about
our incredible sponsor, Tradezeller.
Tradezeller is the number one trading
tool in the entire trading industry.
Tradezella allows you to become a more
profitable trader. Allows you to make
immense progress as a trader, no matter
if you're a beginner or an advanced
level trader, because it makes
journaling easy. It makes journaling
something that is fun and enjoyable and
something that is interactive. So, no
matter if you're a crypto trader, no
matter if you're a futures trader, no
matter if you're a forex trader, no
matter if you're a stock trader, all you
have to do is select your broker, your
platform of choice, and connect it to
Tradesella, and it will automatically
sync your trades and pull all of that
data onto the dashboard, making
journaling and finding your edge and
adapting your edge so easy. In
collaboration with Tradzella and Chart
Fanatic specifically, we are actually
getting the playbooks from the episodes
that we're filming with these incredible
verified traders and adding them as
playbooks onto Trade Zela. So, you can
actually go on there and see the rule
sets already predefined. So, make sure
you check that out as well. Now, you can
actually get 10% off your monthly
subscription using CF10 on Tradzella
right now. But more importantly, I would
say CF20 for 20% off your yearly
subscription with Tradezella. The links
for Tradezella are in the description
below. So, make sure you go check them
out. Use CF20, get 20% off your yearly
subscription, become a better trader
today. Now, let's get back to the
episode. These are the pros.
First pro is going to be we have a high
RR
and a high win rate.
>> Okay.
>> Definitely
>> another pro, this could be a pro or a
con. So you're focusing on a small
window of time. So some people may think
that that's a that this that can be in
the middle, but for me that's a big pro.
It's cuz like I I don't have to be
involved in the market all day. I come
during my window. If I see my trade, I
take it. So another pro is small
window
of time.
All right.
Uh I'd say a big pro is that we are
we're taking advantage of trending
market conditions.
Now we'll go into the cons. Oh, another
pro could be tight stops or it could be
a con. I think tight stops are good
because it creates the high win win win
rate for you
>> and the high risk to reward. So, con.
This is number one. Okay. Patience.
>> Yeah, 100%.
>> That's the one that seems to be there.
>> I know you guys may not have this, but
these setups aren't going to occur very
often. I'm going to be completely honest
with you. You're like I said for my USD
pairs 6 to eight entries a year on each
pair. Gold 10 to 15. Okay? So I I know
it sounds crazy. You guys got to just
wait. You want to trade every day. It's
not going to happen. There could be two
weeks where you're not taking a trade.
But think about it like this. When you
have a high win rate and a high RR, that
one trade will trump every other person
who's trading regularly and making
$1,000 a week, a couple thousand a
month. You could do Listen, I did
>> $50,000 in one trade. That That's the
power of the model. You just have to
wait. Okay. So, let's think of another
con here
>> because I think obviously, you know, if
someone's not available for that
particular window.
>> Yes. Yes. You're right. Small time
window. I keep forgetting that everyone
doesn't have access to the, you know, to
be able to trade the same window as me.
Like in New York, like if somebody's
working, it may be difficult for them to
get access, you know, at 3:00 in the
morning to wake up. You got kids, you
got a family, you know, it's it's
probably hard for them. And I'm I'm
thinking of it in a way because for me,
it's easy. I you know I'm a full-time
trader and I could just wake up and then
go back to sleep. So yes, that is a good
con.
>> What's the um what's the reality of you
take an entry it just goes in your favor
or is there a case where even though
you're getting 10 to 15 per year is it
10 to 15 that you know work out
essentially but is there more entries
signals that are provided but they they
might just be break even because they
didn't move away. Does that make sense?
>> Yeah. Is that the case or no?
>> I have like if I have a break even it's
maybe one of those. Okay, I
>> I'm going to be honest. The win rate is
the win rate is really high. The win
rate if you wait for the setup and you
know it's A+
>> the win rate's like n like it really
doesn't lose much. I know it sounds
crazy, but I've done it. Like I
literally you can go on my Twitter and
see my data. Like I've I've literally
like I don't go through accounts. I
don't ch accounts. Like I just wait.
>> So when I'm patient, the trade is most
likely going to win.
>> So that's all you have to do is this is
the biggest thing is just sitting on
your hands and just waiting for the
market to come to you. I'd say the only
other one that stands out to me would be
that, you know, high-risisk reward
trading, you're handling
uh sort of the the P&L changes. Does
that make sense? So like you could be up
10K, it might come down to six, it might
go up to 20, it might come down to 40.
>> And I want to stress this, if you are
going to use this model, okay,
>> and you're going to trade props, you
have to have, this is crucial, you have
to trade a fully balanced brace based
prop firm. So like Alpha Capital, Think
Capital, FTMO where they're not taking
some of these prop firms, they'll have a
hybrid draw down. So at 5:00 PM when the
when the day closes, right?
>> They're going to take the highest
balance between your equity or equity or
your balance, right? So say you're in a
trade and you're up 10%. And I know the
swing could hit for 25 30%.
>> It's 5:00 now. They're taking the
highest equity of that 10%. The next day
I get a 5% retracement. The account's
burned now.
>> Yeah.
>> How can you How can you're going to
penalize a trader for that? That's
insane. And I tell everybody if you're a
swing trader, you need a fully balanced
based firm. And I believe that the think
about it like this, the best firms in
the in the space are fully balance
based. The only reason why that these
firms are going to have equity based or
hybrid based is so they're going to
tailor these accounts to people who burn
the most accounts. And who are those?
Scalpers and intraday traders. And that
hybrid draw down is only they're not
looking out for you. They just want you
to burn the account. So that's why they
have those rules. So, I tell someone
this, if you're going to try this model
and you want to swing trade on the
higher time frames, have to have a fully
balanced based firm. It's crucial
>> and there are enough out there that you
could just utilize. You don't need to go
with a million of them.
>> Definitely. Definitely. No, I love that.
Let's just add that then in terms of
just the P&L sort of changes.
>> So, uh P N
L Oh, hold on. All right. P&L
fluctuation. Yeah,
>> there you go.
>> Perfect. Well, it's time for the charts,
I think.
>> Yeah, let's get it going.
>> Let's go. So, after that amazing
breakdown, we're now going to look at
the actual strategy on the chart. So,
I'm very much looking forward to it as
well. Drop a comment of your thoughts so
far. Any questions so far, drop it in
the comments below. Make sure you
subscribe. But let's let's do this.
>> Okay. All right. So, if you can remember
what we went over in the on the
whiteboard, we're gonna bring that to
the charts now. the same thing. So what
do we see here? I whenever I this is I
want to stress this when you guys are
doing your back testing you need I do do
all my back testing on Trading View. You
need to have this data. So I write A++
setup like and I have my handwritten
journal where I'm writing what the
candles have done. Like you need to do
all this. It's extremely crucial. This
is what's going to take your trading to
the next level. So with that what do we
see here? Like I said it's hard to see
my EMAs but here's the five I'm talking
told you guys about. Here's the nine.
>> Here's the five. N
>> nine. Here's the five. Here's the nine.
Here's the uh 13 or 15. I don't really
remember which one. And then this is the
21. So now you see, like I said, it's
like a wave. They're all stacking,
right?
>> Mhm.
>> Here's the FG printed at 2:30. Like I
told you, 2:30 and 3:00, those those
fair value gaps are extremely extremely
strong. This is the indicator I told you
guys about where it's showing the
bullish candles. I'll actually bring the
indicator up. It's called bull trading
on on uh trading view.
Bull trading one minute easy scalping.
You change the first time frame to daily
time frame 230 3030. Okay, this this
indicator is really really good. So like
I told you, if these candles are closing
green, it's showing strong bullish price
action. We're in the top of the
Ballinger band above the 200 EMA. I
forgot to stress that in the um
>> in the whiteboard, but if we're above
the 200 EMA, that's my bias. If we're
below, we're looking for shorts. So, I
keep that as like a neutral bias. So, if
we're above the 200
>> structure is bullish. So, now what do
what do I look for? I look for the
trident pattern. Like I told you guys,
here we have this is the this is the leg
of the FG, right?
>> So, one candle, two, three FG is printed
here. We're not worried about this fair
value gap. You know why? Because it's
printed outside of our kill zone.
>> Interesting.
>> Okay. So, we're ignoring that.
>> So, this is the one that gets reacted to
also. So, one, two, three, four. Okay,
this wicks through this fair value gap,
the consequent encroachment of here,
right between these three candles%.
>> Now, we simply set a limit here, stop
loss here,
>> and then you just let it run, kid.
That's it. So, now you're on the 30
minute. Look at what this look at what
this trade did. Okay? You simply just
sit through it.
This is the power of the model.
This ran for okay this is on the daily
time frame. I will even bring this up.
If you want to just solely utilize a 1
to 20 you can. But if you even if you
bring stops to break even here say you
this break a structure and then you
bring stops to be you could listen you
could take my model and use it in a
different way. I'm not saying the way
that I use it you're going to like but
you could take what I'm telling you here
and then make it your own. Like I said
you want to go be here. That's fine. I
just don't do it. Then I go to the daily
chart. Okay, let's see this where this
move was on the daily.
Notice this was the this was the setup
here.
Okay, notice that we just we're we're
just above the 200 EMA. This is all the
EMAs are stacking like I told you the
wave. Yeah,
>> here's the five 9 13 or 15 and 21. We're
>> here's the trade. This is what's going
on inside of this daily candle what I
told you guys about. You see, we're
looking at what's going on here. Now,
>> we just let it run. See, look. Look at
the EMAs are still stacking. You could
cut it here with this IFG like I was
telling you about. Okay,
>> but simply based on here, all the EMAs
are still stacking. So, you could hold
it like this ran for 175 R. I know it's
impossible to hold it for that long, but
say you trim and you just leave a runner
for 20%.
>> You know, like you can make it your own.
I'm not saying the way that I do it is
the best,
>> but you can utilize the way that I'm
telling you to to you guys. and then
really truly make it something powerful.
But as you could see, that's like that
an astronomical risk-to-reward. I just
showed you that it could be done.
There's a high risk-to-reward and it has
a high win rate. But like like I said,
>> there's not many of these setups. You
just got to be patient. You know what I
mean? You have to wait.
>> Let's take a break for a minute there,
guys, cuz I want to tell you about our
incredible partnership with
propfrader.com.
Majority of you out there are prop firm
traders. You're using prop firms to
leverage your trading skills to be able
to get more capital and to be able to
absolutely change your life. So what's
important to be able to find the right
challenge for you with the best firms
and most of all the best prices. And
that is exactly what propfrader.com
does. propertrader.coms allows you to
compare prop firms, be able to find the
best challenge suited to your trading
style, and get you the exclusive best
discounts in the entire industry so that
you're paying the cheapest price
possible for your prop firm challenge.
So on propertrader.com, you'll be able
to use filters to be able to do that and
find the exact challenge for you, be
able to find your favorite prop firms.
Just look on screen right now. You can
see futures firms. You can see CFD firms
with offers up to 50% off, which is
incredible. And you can also see Alpha
Capital there with a one-step challenge
with 25% off using PFT1. And there's so
many more exclusive discounts only on
propertrader.com.
It is the go-to site for all proper
traders out there. And one thing I'm
really excited about that I personally
helped to organize was the giveaway of
giveaways, the seven figure giveaway.
Just through purchasing your challenges
for the best price through
propertrader.com. Every single week, you
will automatically be entered into an
incredible giveaway, a collaborative
effort across all of these firms on
screen. between 100 to 200k accounts
over seven figures. It means that one
person every single week who's made a
purchase through propertrader.com
will be getting seven figures in
challenges that can completely
revolutionize your trading journey.
Again, all you do is for any of the
firms on propertrader.com,
use the code PFT at checkout and you
will automatically be entered every
single week. The link for
propertrader.com is in the description
below. Now, let's get back to the
episode. Patience pays, you know, and
>> of course,
>> the beautiful thing is that this can
just be one playbook, right? This can be
one playbook. You might have a different
playbook that, you know, allows you to
have a bit more frequency potentially
can be difficult to do cuz then, you
know, to be able to focus on, okay,
when's this one showing versus this one?
It can be. It depends on the playbook
itself, you know, how how um, you know,
mechanical in terms of like what you
need to see to actually start looking
for it and identifying it. But, it's
incredible. And as you said though, you
know, it might go for 175R, you may not
hold it that long, but it's about, you
know, even if you held 10%. So a 17%
trade, you know, just with 10% volume.
>> Yeah. But the least the smallest amount
of RR that I've taken on a trade is 1 to
20. That's like my minimum.
>> Yeah.
>> And I know people are like, how how is
that possible? I created the system to
where cuz everyone always says you can't
have a high RR and a high win rate.
Well, I do. Like there's nothing else to
be said about it. Like you could tell me
that it's not possible, but it is. I
have a lot of people on Twitter that
come for me about that and I'm I'm
telling you the truth. Like I have the
data and I could show it to you that I
have a high RR and a high win rate. My
win rate is like 90%. I just like I said
the setups aren't frequent.
>> And then uh
>> you want to see another I could show you
another one on a different pair.
>> We definitely can. Yeah. In terms of uh
where was the pair?
>> Uh the this was
>> Are these like your London zones? These
uh
>> Okay. Yeah. You see these lines? This
this line this is my sessions indicator.
So I just use that to show myself where
London is and then where where I'm
basically looking for a trade. And then
outside of this this is what you is is
powerful is that these black this black
here you're not interested in price
action. So when you're back testing you
don't care about what's going on here.
You just care about what's going on in
this small amount of time.
>> Allows you to sort of get more
simplified. That's what I'm saying is
that when you when you're okay, now
you're focusing on this small window.
Now, now you could dive into each
candlestick and on a 30inut time frame
in that small amount of time. Think
about how many candlesticks that you're
looking at. Not many.
>> Mhm.
>> So, now you're just focusing on the
highest probability candles,
>> you know? So, let me show another one
here.
>> Let me show a UJ one because I really
like U.J, too.
See, like as you can see, like look
here, there's no trades. None. None.
Zero trades. Look, we're not interested
in it. See, it's not This is like a
couple months.
>> How How far in advance are you sort of
identifying the potential for a trade?
Is it literally on the day or
>> on the day? On the day.
>> On the day. So, I come to I come on the
daily turn on the day.
>> Well, if my daily chart is below the 200
EMA, I'm not looking for longs. I'll be
short biased. Yeah. You know what I
mean? So, if I do take a trade, right,
and say my higher time frame, the 4 hour
and the daily is below the 200 EMA, and
I get a long setup, I will I'll cut it
earlier because I know that the the
higher time frame is bearish. Yeah.
>> So, maybe I'll do like on those trades
like 10 to 15 are, and I'm cool with
that.
>> But the biggest trades I have is when
you're aligned with the higher time
frames, of course.
>> So, here's another one here. See?
That one's outside. That's a That's a
higher time. That's a different method.
I have a few models that I utilize now
because
I've gotten better with um navigating
the higher time frames. So, here's
another one here. This is a big one.
Here we go. Now, we're above the 200
EMA. We're inside a London kill zone.
This fair value got printed at 4 am,
which is still it's not as highly
probable as a 2:30 or three, but
especially on UJ, which is in my back
testing, it's a really strong pair for
me. So, what do we see here? This is the
fair value gap we care about. We don't
there's none here. So, we care about
this one. We also get this breaker
structure here above this is uh my Asian
uh range, which is also I I utilize I
like to see all the sessions here. So, I
get this breaker structure above the
Asian range. We're above the 200 EMA. I
get this 50%. Look at this candle. This
is what I want to stress is look at the
wick on this candle. It's a strong dogee
candle. This
>> this is the trident pattern. So between
one, two, three, it looks like the staff
of a trident,
>> but it's just the opposite way. So I
just came up with a cool name for myself
to remember it. And it actually I
actually love the name of it. So
>> you could see here this is our our fair
value gaps printed 1 2 3. We get this
candle. This candle doesn't close above
this high. Say this candle this closed
this candle closed above this high. I
invalidate the setup. It's not valid.
You want this candle to close below. Now
you see
>> why why would it invalidate it?
>> It's just based on my data. It's just
not as highly probable. So I don't take
it.
>> Like it. Granted, it could win, but it's
just it's going to diminish the the win
rate. It's just these little nuance
things is what I've really made. That's
what I'm telling you. I've analyzed
everything.
>> So everything that I've journaled, I go,
okay, how can I make this to the point
where it really never loses?
>> Yeah. And that simple little thing right
there is not taking that candle
increased my win rate astronomically. So
it's just a small little thing like
that. So now once I see this candle I
get the confirmed tried and setup
>> hits the 50%. This is a dogey candle. I
set my you could even enter here.
There's no need to set a limit because
it closed inside the range. Stop loss
here. Like I told you guys here was a a
9 pip stop. I mean that's really small.
And this thing ran. You could after this
break. crazy as well is that it's USD
JPY. So it's not even anything to do
with pound or euro for example JPY is
one of my favorite pairs to trade.
>> It's incredible. Yeah. What's also
interesting as well is that a lot of
people's strategies would be like to
take Asia high and then target Asia low,
right? But in this case, we've taken
Asia high. That's where the entry pretty
much comes in. But then it look, you
know, it's worked out incredible.
>> And then this RR was uh let's see and
we'll just go off the 30 minute. Like
even if you set stops the BE here,
right? And you say you wanted to take
partials. This ran for
>> because that was the thing like one to
28.
>> Exactly. Yeah. To your point as you said
earlier regardless like the the entry
model for it to be as successful they
would probably need you know people
would have to replicate you know to a te
for sure
>> but in terms of the management side
that's where it's you know down to the
individual and that is really any
strategy wise that's really the bit that
>> will make it profitable not for the
individual. Does that make sense? So
like someone might not be able to handle
one to 20 right? Well, that's what I'm
saying is that I have the psychology to
sit on my hands and know a lot of people
don't have that. They're like, when I
had my um think capital path, they're
like, "How did you sit through it that
long?" I go, "I just trusted my model."
>> And it's not for everyone. Like I said,
it may not be. You may only take like a
one to five. That's cool. And you can
put on a little bit more risk. I just
prefer to just sit on the trade and let
it run, you know? But like I said, I'm
telling you right now, if you're patient
enough to and you can nail this uh
strategy down, it'll set you financially
free 100%.
>> Guaranteed. I'm telling you, you just
got to be patient.
>> Incredible. Yeah, that patience is big
though, right? That patience is big
>> and definitely utilize the indicator
that I showed you guys is the um the one
with See, if these candles were like I
want to stress this, if these candles
weren't green like this and they were
red and blue,
>> Yeah.
>> it would be an invalidated setup. You
don't take it because it's not the
market conditions aren't there.
>> It's not showing the momentum, right?
>> Exactly. So, these candles are closing
green and and black, which shows highly
probable conditions for the trade to go
in your favor. And then if you look up
the
>> Was it this trade here?
>> No, it'll be the one. Go. Let's see
where we are. No, we're in 2023.
Go this way.
>> This way.
>> Yeah, it was I think it was it was here
where I wrote A+ setup. It's over here.
>> It's right here, I think.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Zoom in.
>> Well, this Yeah, that one. See, this one
was below this one was below the 200
EMA. But notice, like I showed you guys
in the on the whiteboard, all of the
EMAs are stacking.
>> Yeah.
>> You see, you're just riding. This is
like a this is like a wave a trend wave
I call it. And so I know it's it may be
a lot for you guys to digest, but I
utilize ICT concepts, kill zones, and
then momentum that if I were to put it
in in a simplistic way, that's what I
do. just ride the trend and then wait
for an entry criteria that's showing you
what's going on inside of this candle.
So, you want to know what's the
narrative of this candle. Now, you get
the confirmed setup that this candle
wants to go higher and that's it.
>> I love it.
>> Yeah. So, I listen I think it's an
amazing model. It's not It's literally
one of one. I I haven't seen anybody
else trade anything like this in the
space.
>> No, definitely. Neither have I. Neither
have I. I think high risk to reward it
requires uh as you said a lot of
patience and you know most people
probably will struggle with that you
know especially not only the patient
size because a lot of people a few years
ago when they were trying to do high
risk reward
>> it was high risk reward but frequency
was quite high still like so they're
basically just one minute time frames
you can't
>> and trying to like basically handle
getting stop stopped and then try and
get a move
>> but I think psychologically that's so
difficult you know to to be able to
accept losses or break evens over and
over and over and over like if you have
30% win rate, but your RR is high, it's
it's going to crush your psychology.
Really, like you are not going to be
able to handle that. Losing 70% of your
trades, there's no way.
>> Definitely. Well, Tyler, it's been an
absolute pleasure. I appreciate you
breaking this down for us and really
giving us this insight into your trades.
Um, you know, like I said, a phenomenal
unique system and more success to you as
well. You continued success, absolutely
crushing it. Everyone at home, drop a
comment with your biggest takeaway from
this episode. I know it's a very unique
strategy. Any questions, throw them in
the chat. Tyler will be there. I'll be
there. Links for Tyler will be in the
description below as well. Hit
subscribe. Hit like. Other episodes are
on screen. And this has been Chart
Fanatics. Take it.